Zidan B. Younis

Mobile (+962) 79 6736326 **DOB – POB** 20 July 1981 – Kuwait

Emailzidanyounis@gmail.comNationalityJordanianLanguagesArabic, EnglishMarital StatusMarried

Summary

Through my 20 years in the field of information technology, I worked in various sectors and industries, which made me have a wide culture in developing and understanding enterprise solutions.

I worked in small companies and I was responsible for the project from A to Z, and I also worked in large companies within large and professional work teams.

All of the above helped to form my skills in business analysis professionally and to assume all my responsibilities of requirements gathering, analyzing them, following them up and delivering them to the client.

Skills

Technical Skills

- ASP.Net C#
- SQL Server
- Front-End development
- Team Foundation Server (TFS)

Soft Skills

- Very good communication skills
- Training and presentation skills

Skills

- Project management PMP
- Agile\Scrum
- Business analyzing
- Creating presentations and demos
- Writing Proposals, technical write-ups, user guide and presentations
- Gantt-chat plans

Experience

Perfect Presentation - Ministry of Justice

(Riyadh - Saudi Arabia)

Senior Business Analyst (12/2019 - Present)

Working in a big Agile-Scrum environment in Ministry of Justice - Executive courts system.

This system is serving millions of users through online portals and judges systems. My responsibility is to:

- Working with business stake-holders (Business owner, Delivery manager, Scrum Master, Technical team and QA team)
- Get the requirements from business owner, documents or third-parties meeting
- Create analyzing presentation to get Business owners approval
- Writing BRD
- Writing user-stories on TFS
- Set meetings with any external parties if we need to integrate with
- Support development team in understanding requirements
- Demonstrate requirements to the business owner
- Train new staff
- Analyze integration services requirements

eSense Software

(Amman - Jordan)

Implementation Engineer / Business analyst (10/2016 – 10/2019)

I was reporting directly to COO, and I have several responsibilities as below: My Responsibilities:

- Working with business stake-holders (Client, Project manager, Technical team and QA team)
- Traveling to client's country and city
- Requirements gathering

- Writing BRD
- Handle UAT with the client's team
- Train client users
- Train company's new employees
- · Make system user guide
- Support the QA team with understanding Business, correct behaviors, bugs priorities
- Presales tasks (such as live demonstration for potential customers)
- Project coordinator (Manage PMs relation with clients)
- Consultant for the product (Business-whys and technically)
- Support PMs in Project monitoring and control
- Coordinating between client and company team
- Deploy system releases/Fixes/Updates into the client's environment
- Acting as a Team Leader position when needed
- Acting as a Project Manager position when needed
- Help PMs in project planning

Previous Experience

(8/2001 - 10-2016)

Projects:

- LMS (Learning Management System)
- DMS (Documents Management System)
- Workflow system
- Financing workflow system
- Online portal (Custom CMS for TV network)
- Hospital Management System
- Inventory Management System
- CRM system

Roles:

- Web developer
- Business/System analyst
- Project manager
- Trainer
- Implementer

Education

Corllins University (Online Studying) 2007 - 2010

Bachelors, Computer Science

Arab Collage (Amman - Jordan) 1999 - 2001

Diploma, Information Technology

Trainings

Al-Jitawi Training Center (Amman - Jordan) 2009

PMP (Project Manager Professional) - Attendance Certificate

Microsoft (Online) 2005

MCP (Microsoft Certified Professional) in Visual Basic .NET